we've been given an array which you can
see on line
one and then we've been given three
method calls
on lines three five and seven and we
need to determine what each method will
return
so let's paste this array into irb
[Music]
now the first method we see is the index
method this method is going to return
the
index of the first object in the array
that is equal to the argument so in this
case we've passed
in the argument five now looking at our
array we can see that we have
two fives in our array but the method
documentation has told us that ruby will
return the index of the first
element that matches the argument so
looking at the position
of the first 5 in our array and knowing
that array indexes
are 0 based we expect that the return
value here will be 3.
the first 5 in this array is at index 3.
and that's what we see the next line of
code we've been given
it looks like we are trying to access
the
array element at index five
and in this case that's the integer
eight however this syntax is going to
raise an error
the square brackets look similar to
array element reference
but rather than using the index method
we're going to use this array element
reference on the array itself
and when i run that code we see 8 is
returned
so we can access elements in an array
based on their index
and we can access the index of a given
element in an array
just be sure to remember that the index
method
only returns the index of the first
occurrence of that element